icheme.org 2009-12-17

# icheme.org | Privacy Policy

#### Privacy policy

##### Background

IChemE respects the privacy of its customers and aims to act consistently with the Data Protection Act 1998. IChemE will hold and use data contained on you for administrative purposes, to keep you informed of activities, and to offer goods and services provided by the Institution.

##### How we handle your personal information 

Personal information is information or opinion that allows others to identify you. It includes your name, age, gender and contact details. It is the express wish of the Council that information relating to customers is available only to IChemE and not for direct access by third parties.

##### Collection of personal information

Generally, IChemE collects personal information directly from you. For example, we collect personal information when you:

  * Deal with IChemE in person, by telephone, letter, fax or email 
  * Supply a resume 
  * Fill out and submit a membership application form 
  * Submit any other information in connection with your application for membership or the purchase of products and services 
  * Make an enquiry via a web form on any of the IChemE websites 
  * Complete your subscription renewal forms 

Personal information about you may also be collected from a third party. For example when IChemE receives:

  * References relating to your application 
  * Information about you relating to reciprocal relationships we have with other professional associations 

#####   
Why we collect information 

We collect your personal information to enable us to provide various products and services and for the administration of your membership with the Institution.

##### What we collect

The type of personal information we collect includes your title, first name, surname, gender, date of birth, nationality, your qualifications, home and work contact details (phone, fax, email, street address, email address) and your mailing address. We also collect information relating to your employment including where you are currently employed, your job title, areas of interest/ expertise and your job function. As part of the membership application process we collect information relating to your qualifications (proof of completion, academic transcripts). In applications for some grades of membership we ask you to identify a referee and to provide contact information for them. When purchasing a product, your credit card details are also collected, and are temporarily stored until we have processed your order.

##### Use and disclosure

IChemE's policy is not to disclose any personal Information that we hold on you to any unrelated third party, except where you have given your express consent for us to do so or where required by law.

Arrangements are occasionally made with suppliers of goods and services for their mailings to be sent to members. All material is carefully vetted and the mailing list is never released to third parties.

We provide your email address to the Special Interest Groups of IChemE for the purpose of notifying you about events and activities of these groups.

If you tell us that you do not wish us to use your Personal Information for a particular purpose, we will not do so.

##### Sending personal information overseas

For members who live outside the UK data may be transferred to their local centre.

##### Security 

IChemE uses all reasonable efforts to ensure Personal Information provided by you is held securely.

Information to improve our site   
We also collect information automatically about your visit to our site. This information is used to help us follow browsing preferences on our site so that we can regularly improve our web site.

##### Access to personal information

You can seek access to the personal information we hold about you, by contacting us. If the information we hold about you is inaccurate, incomplete, or outdated, please inform us so that we can correct it.

##### Contact us about our privacy and information handling practices

If you have any questions, comments or would like further information about our privacy and information handling practices, please contact: 

Justin Blades  
Institution Of Chemical Engineers  
Davis Building  
165 - 189 Railway Terrace  
Rugby  
CV21 3HQ  
United Kingdom

Telephone: + 44 01788 578214  
Facsimile: + 44 01788 560833  
Email: [jblades@icheme.org](mailto:jblades@icheme.org)

##### Unsubscribe Statement

In accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998, IChemE (and companies processing data on its behalf) currently hold and use data held on you for administration purposes, to keep you informed of its activities, and offer goods and services provided by the Institution. 

We would stress that your personal data is available only to IChemE and not for direct access by third parties. Mailing arrangements are occasionally made with third party suppliers of goods and services but all material is carefully vetted and the mailing list is never released to them.

If you wish to be removed from any of our mailing lists, please contact:

Justin Blades  
Institution Of Chemical Engineers  
Davis Building  
165 - 189 Railway Terrace  
Rugby  
CV21 3HQ  
United Kingdom

Telephone: + 44 01788 578214  
Facsimile: + 44 01788 560833  
Email: [jblades@icheme.org](mailto:jblades@icheme.org)
